Hey everyone, Kate here.
GPT 5.6 is finally here.
And with its release,
The Codex and ChatGPT apps have also seen some major changes.
So now, these two apps have been merged into one.
The app is now called ChatGPT.
We can now use Codex right within the app.
And if you select the Codex mode,
If you're using the GPT 5.6 Sol model,
It costs twice the points of GPT 5.5.
So, in my experience today,
I can definitely tell that my Pro membership with the 5x multiplier is just not cutting it anymore.
I even had to reset it once.
In fact, OpenAI itself even had to reset things once today.
So now, GPT comes in three different product forms.
First is Chat, which is what we're used to on the official website or on our phones.
You can have quick conversations, ask and answer questions, analyze data, and write content.
And now, there's a new mode called 'Work'.
It's a lot like Claude's Cowork.
It can help us create spreadsheets, documents, PPTs,
websites, and so on.
So, what about the GPT 5.6 Sol model?
It performs exceptionally well across multiple benchmarks.
When it comes to professional work,
it actually surpasses Fable 5 on several benchmarks.
When it comes to coding,
Now, the GPT 5.6 Sol model and the Fable 5 model each have their own strengths.
And when it comes to scientific and health-related questions,
The 5.6 Sol model, on the other hand, has some very clear advantages.
The 5.6 Sol model is also exceptionally good when it comes to computer use.
And as for Codex itself,
Its computer use capabilities are just better than Claude's.
Additionally, in areas like cybersecurity, self-improvement, research acceleration, and multimodality...
And in academia,
GPT-5.6 performs exceptionally well across multiple benchmarks.
And this time, OpenAI is putting a special emphasis on its stronger performance per dollar.
In other words, you can get more successful tasks done with the same budget.
So, what they're really, subtly implying here is...
Claude, you're just too expensive.
And on the AI Arena leaderboard,
The GPT 5.6 Sol Max model has now climbed to the number two spot.
And some content creators have been sharing their feedback.
5.6 Sol is actually more practical than Fable 5.
Fable 5, on the other hand, performs better when it comes to judgment and understanding user intent.
5.6 is particularly good at coordinating sub-agents.
But if you want to use the Ultra mode,
Then it's going to burn through a ton of tokens.
So, right now, I'm inside the new ChatGPT app.
I can't even select the Ultra mode.
I'm on the 5x Pro membership.
So, as you can see, there's an 'Extremely High' option, which corresponds to 'x-high'.
And then there's 'Extremely High'.
and it will use up your quota faster.
This is the Max mode. If you go to the GPT web interface, you'll see there's an 'Extra High' option.
Then there's Pro. Pro users can opt for the 5.6 Sol model.
And if we switch over to Work mode...
you'll see an Ultra mode.
And this time, OpenAI also put a special emphasis on...
is the huge leap in their design capabilities.
So, from my own experience,
And it's true, the pages it creates now...
The pages it generates now are, without a doubt, a huge improvement over what it could do before.
GPT-5.6 Sol on OSWorld.
This is based on the computer use benchmark.
It surpasses Opus 4.8.
Plus, its output tokens are reduced by 85%.
Additionally, 5.6 Sol also enhances its capabilities for PPT documents.
and the quality of spreadsheets.
However, the output from 5.6 Sol will more closely follow the structure and color scheme of the original file you provided.
So, for those of you who are currently paying users on the Chat page,
can use GPT 5.6 Sol.
Now, in ChatGPT Work,
Pro users, on the other hand, get access to the Ultra mode.
This will activate four agents to work on the task simultaneously.
Alright, let's take a look at the new Work mode that GPT just rolled out.
And we can see this on both mobile and the web.
Right now, you have two tabs: Chat and Work.
And on the ChatGPT app,
On the left, you can choose between Work or Codex.
On top of that, the OpenAI engineers also shared some other upgrades.
The in-app browser is now more powerful.
It supports verified sites.
multiple tabs,
Plus, you can download files, and there's a new Chrome extension.
This lets GPT work with you right inside the browser to get things done.
So, just click on the browser extension.
Let's ask it to give us a rundown of this news article.
And then we'll get a complete answer like this.
And its UI, including its official website, is still very consistent.
So, what we're looking at now is the old Codex pet.
And now, it's become the new pet for the ChatGPT app.
And now, let's give GPT a task.
Let's have it polish up this Keynote.
And for the new computer usage feature,
Then, a small window will pop up right next to the pet.
And with this window, you can either click on it or just hover over it.
making it super easy to see what's going on.
So, where are we at with this?
And if it's using multiple apps at the same time,
So, all we have to do is get close to this pet,
you'll also see multiple small windows like this pop up.
And for developers,
Codex has also received some upgrades.
You can edit files directly.
You can view and review pull requests without ever leaving the app.
You can also use Pro mode within Chat.
So in Codex, I'm just going to open up a chat.
A pop-up will appear on the right side.
And just like that, we can use GPT's Pro model.
Alright, let me show you my hands-on test.
So, I've selected the Work mode on the web version.
I went with the 5.6 Sol x-high model.
So, I gave it this picture,
and then I'll have it identify how many bugs there are.
And it only took a little over four minutes.
And it correctly identified all five bugs, with their positions being spot on.
It used the image cropping feature,
and then zoomed in.
And finally, it correctly identified all five bugs.
So, in my recent tests,
The Sonnet 5 Max, however, was successful.
Fable 5 High, on the other hand, did not succeed.
Now, for the GPT web interface,
It can now also display all sorts of interactive visualizations.
For example, let me give it a prompt here.
It's been working for a bit,
And it gave me this: a visualization for a physics problem.
A visualization for a physics problem.
Next, in Work mode, I'm going to give it a problem like this.
and have it create a PowerPoint presentation.
Overall, the pages it generated have a really nice look and feel.
Now, when we get to the fifth page...
you'll see that the table it made is just really rough.
As for the content on the other pages,
So I gave it a quick look-over,
I feel like it did a really great job, though.
GPT's search capabilities are incredibly powerful.
So, having it handle this task was an absolutely brilliant move.
In the end, it took almost 19 minutes.
to help me complete this task.
Now, let's look at the webpage for a pair of headphones, created using the 5.6 Sol mode.
So, we can see the overall look of these headphones.
The brushed metal texture is very well done.
The structure of the earcups is also well done.
But the thing is, the earcups feel disconnected from the headband.
And as we scroll down, you can clearly see the 5.6 Sol.
And this time around, the web design is definitely a step up.
And down below, you can select different colors.
In the previous tests, we had multiple models.
So, when it comes to the color selection here,
It's designed to be very minimalist.
It just added a 2D element.
and displays a rather ugly one.
And down below, the technical specs are also really well done.
So, why did it take so long?
Because before it actually generates the application,
First, it calls upon an image generation tool to create multiple images.
So, when I first saw the images it generated,
I was thinking, the page it generates this time is definitely going to be pretty awesome.
So, what if we give it another picture?
and have it create a music player like this.
For those of you who've seen my previous videos,
Don't you think this 5.6 Sol model is the best one yet?
When I first saw this design,
I was absolutely blown away.
I mean, the result it produced was just incredible.
But then, I took a look at the code and realized...
It actually uses a really clever trick here.
It took the picture I sent it at the very beginning,
and placed it at the very bottom layer of the entire canvas.
and then processed it a bit.
And it's also made to be responsive.
Whether you adjust it to the width of a phone or a computer screen,
I couldn't even tell the difference.
Oh, so there was an image down here all along.
So, after setting up the base image,
So, I sent this picture over to GPT.
and asked it to replicate the design and generate the HTML.
And the result it generated... I was absolutely blown away.
I was thinking it was just trying to fudge it with a single image.
and just plop the image onto the webpage?
But then I realized something was off.
And after I clicked on it,
And a lot of the content on the page is actually interactive.
And right here, we can even select different weather conditions.
Close-up, wide-angle, standard.
or the scene themes on the left.
Even the windshield wipers here.
And the intensity here.
I'm just wondering when GPT will be able to do a restoration this precise.
And many of the elements on the page...
And it looks like the area it's selected is also spot on.
Of course, right now, there's still a lot of content that needs to be modified.
But to get this kind of result from just a single prompt...
Personally, I'm still very satisfied with it.
Because I saw in its thought process...
It mentioned using an 'image-to-code' skill, so I asked it right away,
So where is this skill installed?
Is that one of your built-in skills?
And it told me that this falls under product design.
It's part of the plugins.
Plus, there's the audit skill.
URL to code, and the index skill.
And then there's the 'index' skill, making it four skills in total.
So, here's what they do.
So, its 'index' skill is what makes these determinations.
So, if a user requests to build a webpage based on this screenshot,
Then it will call upon the 'image to code' function.
If the request is to replicate the webpage's UI 100%,
it will route the request to URL to code.
Plugins like URL to code and Codex are just incredibly useful.
On top of the model's outstanding capabilities,
And on top of that, all its plugins are incredibly well-designed.
And now, let's take a look at the desktop planetarium generated by GPT 5.6.
The quality of the output is also just fantastic.
For instance, we can take a look at the Earth right here.
and it looks incredibly realistic, just like the real thing.
Now, let's look at the 3D magic cube it generated in x-high mode.
There are a few preset shapes.
But I gave it a try,
But in this case, 5.6 Sol didn't do a particularly great job.
So, I guess we'll just have to wait for GPT 6 and see what that brings.
But for this page generated by 5.6 Sol,
I think it's super clean and I really like it.
So, before we actually create it,
First, we'll use GPT Image 2 to generate an image like this.
a reference image.
I think the level of detail it captured is incredibly high.
Now, let's take a look at the Suzhou Museum generated by GPT.
It did take quite a while, though.
It must have taken 30 minutes.
The texture of this盆景 of the迎客松, or the Guest-Greeting Pine, is actually really good.
Plus, the image is really flickering a lot.
Overall, it's not bad.
Here's the image it generated initially.
Alright, next, I'm going to have 5.6 Sol put together a complete, up-to-date financial report for Tesla.
So, how about analyzing this data?
I need it to fetch the data on its own.
It took it 40 minutes to get this done for me.
Here's the Excel spreadsheet it delivered.
This layout is already a significant improvement over what I tested last time.
back with GPT 5.5.
It actually includes multiple sheets.
And you can also see the dashboard it generated.
A visual preview for this quarter.
So, we've got the summary, some financial charts... and yeah, they all look pretty good.
And as for the original file...
And it's also listed some for me here.
This includes the presentation file from the official financial report.
So I went ahead and sent it this picture as well.
and have it generate a 3D modeling software.
It also checked my local OpenSCAD.
But for the Mac version of OpenSCAD, there's a problem.
I mean, the difference between its development build and its official release version.
and they're quite different from each other.
The one I have installed on my computer is the development version.
At first, it didn't recognize it.
So then, it went ahead and tried to download the official 2021 version for me.
So, when I saw this,
So I quickly stopped it.
and told it where I had it installed on my computer.
After that, it started using my local version.
And then it starts rendering.
Now, this surface, compared to the original image I sent it...
are still very different.
In the original image, there wasn't any brand logo on the surface at all.
So, when it rendered this image,
Personally, I think the watch strap and the stitching are both really well done.
And also, when 5.5 was generating it, uh...
The watch face and the strap are separate.
Plus, it has four raised bumps.
But now, with 5.6 Sol,
But now, the 5.6 Sol doesn't have that problem.
With 5.6 Sol, its restoration is identical to the original image.
As for the dial,
There's still a bit of a difference, though.
This includes the visualized mechanics.
The structure should be in the upper-left section of the dial.
Next, let's look at a traffic light simulation generated by GPT 5.6.
Alright, so let's take a look at the current page.
And the design style of this GPT page...
Personally, I'm a big fan of this. Alright, let me just adjust the speed first.
So, if we crank it up to 4, the vehicles here...
One car and another car.
This kind of clipping is actually pretty severe.
And then we'll see all sorts of turns.
And the cars just drive straight through them.
Plus, the placement of the traffic lights is also off.
But the clean and uncluttered layout of this page...
I'm a huge fan of this, honestly.
Now, let's take a look at the 'Along the River During the Qingming Festival' scroll it generated.
Let's take a look along the river.
Yesterday, I showed you the results GPT 5.5 generated on the same task.
Personally, I think...
version 5.6.
So, two models.
There are some issues with the way the bridge is constructed.
Alright, let's switch up the angle now.
This is a panoramic view.
And then, we have the crowd on the bridge.
Alright, so as for the bridge right now...
I don't see the person leading the ox.
Let's switch again. Under the bridge, there are boatmen.
Let's switch to a bird's-eye view of the city gate.
Now, what about the shop signs on both sides generated by 5.6 Sol?
It's not super clear.
And the signs themselves...
And the results are a far cry from what Fable 5 generated.
So, this application you're seeing on the screen right now...
Yeah, that was me. I had GPT 5.5 High generate this for me a couple of days ago.
So today, I've gone with the 5.6 Sol x-high.
So,
to give me some suggestions on how to improve this app.
So, for the 5.6 Sol...
First, it uses the audit skill to check the visual interaction and information structure.
So, at that time, my phone...
It wasn't connected to the computer via wireless debugging.
It was in wireless mode.
and then it found my device.
And it even turned on the wireless debugging mode on my phone.
and then took screenshots of my app.
So, this is what it came up with. The plan it wrote is actually incredibly detailed.
And inside, it lists a bunch of issues it found from the screenshots.
For instance, it flagged my outer screen's home page as being 'unhealthy'.
As for the settings page, it thinks it needs a complete redesign.
And here's the dark mode reading experience on the inner screen.
It thinks this green color is not conducive to reading.
Here's the two-column table of contents for the inner screen.
It thinks the structure is good.
However, the width strategy needs some adjustment.
Next up is the light theme for in-app reading.
And for all these pages it found, it clicked on them all by itself.
and then take a screenshot.
So, to start with, for this task, I chose the Plan mode.
So, along the way, it also asked me a few questions.
Uh...
So, I had it work on the visuals first.
So, after I had it run,
It took a little while to process this as well.
Similarly, it first called upon an image generation tool to create three concept images.
And I think it does a really great job with this.
It shows me the images first to see if I'm satisfied.
This can reduce friction.
Plus, the quality of the images it generates is incredibly high.
I just used my own screenshot directly.
The final result is incredibly faithful to the original.
Then, I also had the 5.6 Sol high model...
So, let's see...
to help me develop a watermarking app.
And it took it nearly 19 minutes to build.
It's going to run into some bugs along the way.
It just keeps running in a loop on its own.
without any intervention from me.
Of course, in the prompt, when we're building a macOS app,
It's best to make the call.
This is a plugin officially released by OpenAI.
The one on the left is generated by 5.6.
and on the right is the one generated by 5.5.
And you can clearly tell the difference with 5.6.
And this time, the UI is a bit better.
When I import a video, a watermark automatically appears at the bottom.
And over here on the right, I can click to randomly generate different styles for this watermark.
And you can choose from a few different styles.
You can also adjust things like how often it appears, and so on.
One thing I think is really great about 5.6 Sol is
First off, it makes the video preview look much more advanced.
and it has rounded corners.
And it also has this transparent, shadowy effect.
I'm sure many of you are also using Matte, and you'll notice the preview position for the watermark insertion at the bottom.
And they've done a pretty good job with this part as well.
Many users have reported that it tends to ask a lot of questions, and its style is quite distinctive.
So, when it came to developing this app with 5.5...
At first, it only showed my profile picture.
without showing my name.
But with 5.6, it got it right in one go.
But version 5.6 did run into a problem here as well.
At first, it couldn't load the video.
But of course, this was a relatively minor issue for it.
But it fixed that pretty quickly.
And finally, I had it check the app for any performance issues.
privacy leaks.
I also had it generate an app icon.
and install it into the app.
So, the first icon it generated looked something like this.
with a square corner.
And it was also larger than the other icons.
Then, 5.6 used the magenta color.
and generates a true transparent alpha for the background in the middle.
Then it makes the background transparent, and here's the final icon design it generates.
It's quite aesthetically pleasing, actually.
Finally, let's check out two more examples from the 5.6 Sol High mode.
So, uh, here are some videos made in Hi mode.
I think what it came up with is actually pretty interesting.
The first one is a short skit based on Chinese idioms.
For the second one, I sent it the news link for GPT 5.6.
and then I had it create an introductory video.
And I think for these two videos,
The quality of both is actually quite impressive.
And for our final video, let's do a quick recap.
So, what exactly did GPT 5.6 just drop?
Welcome to the Idiom Short-Play Theater!
Today, let your little bookworm guide you through some animations.
Four stories, four little pieces of wisdom.
A farmer found a rabbit.
Waiting for the hare by the stump.
He thought he'd get lucky every day.
He was over the moon.
But, the rabbit never came again.
He put down his hoe,
He waited by the tree stump day after day.
Don't just rely on luck; you have to put in the work.
But his crops withered.
You can't just rely on luck.
You have to make an effort.
A thief wanted to steal the bronze bell.
The bell rang, and he covered his ears.
The bell jingled loudly.
If I cover my ears, no one else will hear it either, right?
He thought no one else could hear it either.
He's just fooling himself.
But deceiving yourself doesn't solve the problem.
An artist was painting a dragon.
All that was missing were the final touches to its eyes.
But it still lacked a certain spark of life.
He picked up the brush and gently painted in the eyes.
With the final touch, the dragon seemed to come to life!
With a flash of golden light,
One final, crucial stroke that brings the whole thing to life.
A single, crucial stroke can bring the whole thing to life.
Act Four
The *** broken, and the little lamb has run away.
We have to fix the sheep pen, and fast!
The little sheep will be safe from now on.
And the little lamb is found.
Something went wrong.
It's not too late to fix it.
Every idiom tells a story.
Four little words of wisdom.
And wisdom can be found in stories.
See you next time for more of our idiom skits!
See you next time.
July 2026.
OpenAI has released GPT-5.6.
Its core focus isn't just on stacking more parameters,
but in making every token deliver more useful work.
This tier is broken down into three flagship levels.
Then there's TARA for general-purpose work, and the fastest one,
and LUNA, the most cost-effective one.
So, 'Sol' is OpenAI's most powerful coding model to date.
scoring 80 points on the Coding Agent Index.
all while using less than half the output tokens and time.
Fewer tokens, faster completion, and better performance for the price. It trades more computing power for stronger results.
When it comes to more challenging tasks,
Max will dedicate more time to reasoning.
Ultra mode defaults to coordinating four agents to work in parallel.
This trades higher computational power for stronger results and faster task completion.
And this isn't just about reasoning.
GPT-5.6's design judgment has seen a significant leap forward.
It can review the actual interface based on high-level requirements.
and iterates on it until it's ready for delivery.
In end-to-end knowledge work,
It connects document creation, presentations, spreadsheets, and web browsing into a single, seamless workflow.
The Sol model's browser completion score reached 92.2%.
OSWorld 2.0 reached 62.6%.
Cybersecurity and scientific research are also making strides.
Exploit Bench,
up from 47.9% in GPT 5.5.
to a staggering 73.5%.
Significant improvements have also been seen in life sciences and chemistry benchmarks.
This enhanced capability is also accompanied by stronger safeguards.
OpenAI
This is achieved by combining large-scale automated testing with human red-teaming and layered, real-time monitoring.
and invested in approximately 700,000 A100 GPUs.
and thousands of hours of black-box red-teaming evaluations.
GPT-5.6 is now available in ChatGPT, Codex, and the OpenAI API.
Soul, Tara, Luna.
Make efficiency the default.
Bringing top-tier capabilities to you, right when you need them.